Ankit Pradhan



ankitpradhan2k15@gmail.com



+918097899391



Bhubaneswar, India



linkedin.com/in/pradhan-ankit

About Me

Product Manager and Strategist with expertise in growth, and digital innovation across various industries. Skilled in enhancing UX, agile project management, and implementing data-driven strategies.

MBA with a global background in technology, product development, and stakeholder management.

Highlights

Birmingham 2022 CW games

Awarded the Commonwealth Games recognition award for being the conduit between the games world and the technology world.

Larsen & Toubro Technology Services

Team of the Year award for FY 2018 - Bagged multiple projects for Embraer KC-390 and Smart cockpit display from South American and Middle-eastern markets.

Durham University

Awarded Durham MBA Merit Scholarship among the top 5 merit students for various session-related activities throughout the term.

Skills

- First Principles Thinking
- Roadmapping
- Ruthless Prioritisation
- Market Research
- Product Led Growth
- Product Analytics
- UX & Design Principles
- Business Strategy
- Stakeholder Management

Professional Experience

Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games | Technology Project manager | Birmingham, UK

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Launched the Games Tracking app, a data collection app, resulting in a 40% increase in the accuracy of data.
- Conducted one-on-one interviews and user surveys, organised platform awareness workshops, and improved the Volunteer Management System's adoption rate by 300% in just six weeks.
- Re-launched the Games Time website with improved UI/UX, tech stack, content, and SEO. Reduced load time from 2.5 to 1.8 seconds; the bounce rate dipped from 77% to 40%.
- Drove sponsors product positioning, resulting in 30% lead conversion and 10% organic traffic gains.

Varicon Aqua | Strategy Consultant | Durham, UK

Jun 2021 - Oct 2021

Key responsibilities:

- Developed and executed a market entry strategy for the EU, expanding into the UK and France, resulting in a 12% market penetration.
- Implemented a referral program that raised the clickthrough rate by 35% and increased user acquisition by 20%.
- Conducted market research to identify key suppliers, achieving a 10% reduction in costs.
- Facilitated cross-functional collaboration between technical experts, BDE, and proposal writers to ensure all info. was included in proposals, resulting in a 25% reduction in post-submission revisions.

Tools and Platform

Analytics: Google Analytics, Mixpanel

A/B Testing: VWO

BI Tools: Microsoft Power BI, Looker studio

Project management: JIRA, Trello, Smartsheet,

ProjectLibre

CRM: Salesforce, ClickUp

UI/UX: Figma, Mural, Canva

Languages: SQL, Python, Ada, Lua

Testing: Vectorcast

Certification

Atlassian - Jira Fundamental Badge - 2023

Product School - Product Strategy Micro-Certification (PSC)™ -2023

Education Background

- Durham University, Durham, UK
 MBA 2021
- SOA University, Bhubaneswar, India

B.Tech - Electronics and Communication engineering - 2015

Larsen & Toubro Technology Services | Senior Engineer | Bengaluru, India

Sep 2015 - Apr 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Analysed user activity data to tailor UX; targeted service removals increased engagement by 40%.
- De-cluttered multiple stages in the product development life cycle with stakeholders, reducing go-to-market time by 33% and enhancing market agility.
- Championed innovative products, igniting excitement among customers and securing interest at top air shows